A Guide to the Norfolk (Va.) Building Inspection Office Architectural Drawings and Plans, 1898-1980
Library of Virginia
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 71768, Address: 1120 Toler Pl., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 8; Tag Number: 1980-224 (Box 72, Folder 1178)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Design 3 Corp.; Commissioned by: Eve Marie Perrenot
- Hofheimer's Shoe Stores- Store # 22, Alterations, Deletions, and Additions, Janaf Shopping Center - Permit Number: 70821, Address: 5900 Virginia Beach Blvd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-158 (Box 72, Folder 1179)
  Drawn by: Gary W. Bright, Architect, A.I.A., 2466 Pleasure House Rd., Virginia Beach, VA; Contractor: C. F. Hardy Building Corp.; Commissioned by: Hofheimer's Shoe Store
- Gonsoulin Duplex - Permit Number: 71897, Address: 9732 12th View St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 10; Tag Number: 1980-285 (Box 72, Folder 1180)
  Drawn by: The Design Collaborative, Principal, Laxzlo Aranyi, A.I.A., 138 Rosemont Rd., Virginia Beach, VA; Contractor: Sea Breeze- David J. Wahl; Commissioned by: Robert E. Gonsoulin
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 71936, Address: 5109 S. Cape Henry Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1980-289 (Box 72, Folder 1181)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Leana C. Hobbs
- [Alterations to] First Baptist Church - Permit Number: 71913, Address: 418 Bute St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: 1980-291 (Box 73, Folder 1182)
  Drawn by: Thomas Construction Co.; Contractor: Thomas Construction Co.; Commissioned by: First Baptist Church
- Three Bedroom Ranch - Permit Number: 71648, Address: 3412 Lens Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1980-212 (Box 73, Folder 1183)
- [Four Family Apartment Building] - Permit Number: 71744, Address: 129 W. Balview Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1980-222 (Box 73, Folder 1184)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Benford Construction Co.; Notes: z
- United Virginia Bank, 8th Floor, Personnel and Property Management - Permit Number: 59950, Address: 5 Main Plaza East, 1978, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: 1978-078 (Box 73, Folder 1185)
  Drawn by: McGaughy, Marshall, and McMillan, A Professional Association, Architects and Consulting Engineers, Norfolk, VA; Washington, DC; Athens, Greece; Richmond, Virginia; Omaha, Nebraska; Contractor: Conrad Bros. Inc.; Commissioned by: United Virginia Bank
- Office and Warehouse Buildings for Progress Associates, Ltd. - Permit Number: 73405, Address: 4575 Progress Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1980-390 (Box 73, Folder 1186)
- Kippenbrock Scales Building Addition Plan for Hezzie Raynor - Permit Number: 68901, Address: 9539 1st View St., 1979, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1979-553 (Box 73, Folder 1187)
  Drawn by: H. R. Schippell, Certified Professional Engineer, 3232 Verdun Ave, Norfolk, VA; Commissioned by: Kippinbrock Scale Service
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 71640, Address: 908 Grayson St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-210 (Box 73, Folder 1188)
- Office-Production Plant - Permit Number: 73301, Address: 1185 Pineridge Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 18; Tag Number: 1980-385 (Box 73, Folder 1189)
  Drawn by: Stroud, Pence Associates, Ltd., Consulting Structural Engineers, 204-A Grayson Rd., Virginia Beach, VA; Contractor: Reale Construction Co.; Commissioned by: Catalytic Generators
- Chi-Chi's - Permit Number: 71564, Address: 1050 N. Military Hwy., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 23; Tag Number: 1980-202 (Box 73, Folder 1190)
  Drawn by: James M. Hamill, Architect, Earl F. McKinney, P. E., 216 E. Reynolds Rd., Lexington, KY; Contractor: C and S Contractors, Inc.; Commissioned by: Mexican Dinner Houses
- [Alterations to Laboratory] - Permit Number: 73086, Address: 700 W. Olney Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: 1980-370 (Box 73, Folder 1191)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Eastern Virginia Medical Authority
- Marine Engine Repair Facility, Bulkhead and Pier - Permit Number: 71828, Address: Foot of S. Main St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1980-227 (Box 73, Folder 1192)
  Drawn by: Glenn-Rollins and Associates, Inc., Consulting Engineers, Norfolk, VA; Contractor: W. F. Magann Corp.; Commissioned by: Virginia Tractor Co.
- Renovations and Additions to Metropolitan A.M.E.Z. Church - Permit Number: 72009, Address: 1706 Springfield Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-298 (Box 73, Folder 1193)
  Drawn by: Livas and Associates, Architects, Norfolk, VA; Contractor: Deloatch Ceiling Co.; Commissioned by: Metropolitan A.M.E.Z. Church
- Mother's Record Store Renovation - Permit Number: 72033, Address: #30 Military Circle Shopping Center, 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-300 (Box 73, Folder 1194)
  Drawn by: Williams and Tazewell and Associates, Inc., Architects, Engineers, Planners, Interior Designers, Norfolk, Virginia Beach; Contractor: C. F. Hardy Building Corp.; Commissioned by: Mother's Record Store
- [Four Family Apartment Building] - Permit Number: 73563, Address: 1565 Lea View Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1980-408 (Box 73, Folder 1195)
  Drawn by: Edwin B. Small, Certified Professional Engineer; Commissioned by: David E. Hope
- Residence for Katherine A. Williams, Ghent Square - Permit Number: 72232, Address: 1328 Botetourt Gardens, 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1980-312 (Box 73, Folder 1196)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Katherine A. Williams
- [Duplex] - Permit Number: 71327, Address: 1410 Moultrie Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 11; Tag Number: 1980-189 (Box 73, Folder 1197)
- Stovall House Renovation for Phyllis Brown - Permit Number: 71865-71866, 72196, Address: 1010 Llewellyn Mews, 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 5; Tag Number: 1980-232 (Box 73, Folder 1198)
  Drawn by: Lewis A. Rightmier, Architect, Virginia Beach, VA; Commissioned by: Phyllis B. Brown
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 71112, Address: 9330 Backman Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1980-178 (Box 73, Folder 1199)
- [C and P Building- Bute Street] Alterations, Phase III and IV - Permit Number: 70652, Address: 120 W. Bute St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 56; Tag Number: 1980-143 (Box 74, Folder 1200)
  Drawn by: Oliver, Smith and Cook, Ltd., Architects-Planners, Norfolk and Virginia Beach, VA; Contractor: Robert R. Marquis, Inc.; Commissioned by: C and P Telephone Co.
- [Alterations to Office] - Permit Number: 71453, Address: 330 Granby Mall, 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-195 (Box 74, Folder 1201)
  Drawn by: D K Design Team, Interior Planners Designers, 7501 Liberty Rd., Baltimore, MD; Contractor: E D B Construction Co., Inc.; Commissioned by: Dr. Stanley J. Levine
- [Addition and Sun Deck] - Permit Number: 71864, Address: 9277 Peachtree St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 14; Tag Number: 1980-231 (Box 74, Folder 1202)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Phillip Otto
- Proposed Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Howard B. Cohen - Permit Number: 70761, Address: 1308 North Shore Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 8; Tag Number: 1980-150 (Box 74, Folder 1203)
  Drawn by: W. A. Schmidt; Commissioned by: Howard B. Cohen
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 73099, Address: 100 E. Gilpin Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-371 (Box 74, Folder 1204)
- Three Bedroom Model A - Permit Number: 72492, Address: 2524 Minnesota Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-329 (Box 74, Folder 1205)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Helfant Bros., Inc.
- [Two Family Residence] - Permit Number: 73271, Address: 4116 Pretty Lake Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1980-381 (Box 74, Folder 1206)
  Drawn by: Baymark Realty Corporation; Commissioned by: Michael Builders
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 71083, Address: 1310 Cloncurry Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1980-176 (Box 74, Folder 1207)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Marguerite O. Brown
- [Two Family Residence] - Permit Number: 71093, Address: 191 DuPont Cir., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 9; Tag Number: 1980-177 (Box 74, Folder 1208)
  Drawn by: Kingsberry Homes, Boise Cascade Corporation; Commissioned by: Ream Development Corp.
- [Duplex] - Permit Number: 71328, Address: 1408 Moultrie Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 11; Tag Number: 1980-190 (Box 74, Folder 1209)
- Dodge's Store, H and D Oil Co. - Permit Number: 71238, Address: 8110 Hampton Blvd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 11; Tag Number: 1980-183 (Box 74, Folder 1210)
  Drawn by: Leon K. Smith, Certified Architect; Contractor: T. W. Alphin; Commissioned by: Henry Dodge
- Two Story Colonial - Permit Number: 73564, Address: 413 Peace Haven Dr., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1980-409 (Box 74, Folder 1211)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Sharlyn Construction Corp.
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 73277, Address: 1119 Botetourt Gardens, 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 9; Tag Number: 1980-382 (Box 74, Folder 1212)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: S and C Corp.
- One Story 2 Bedroom Duplex - Permit Number: 71256, Address: 2425 Wyoming Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1980-185 (Box 74, Folder 1213)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Jack R. Jacovides
- Three Bedroom, Two Story [Residence] - Permit Number: 71368, Address: 5206 Argall Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1980-192 (Box 74, Folder 1214)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: A. P. Doxey, Inc. T/A Old Towne Development Co.
- Addition to Existing Garage - Permit Number: 71144, Address: 8528 Halprin Dr., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1980-179 (Box 74, Folder 1215)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Cecil M. Edwards; Commissioned by: Cecil M. Edwards
- [Single to Two Family Residence Conversion] - Permit Number: 71291, Address: 327 E. Little Creek Rd., 1980, Media: Electrostatic prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-187 (Box 74, Folder 1216)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Dave Riley
- [Alteration to Residence] - Permit Number: 71353, Address: 1452 Ashland Cir., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: 1980-191 (Box 74, Folder 1217)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Park Construction Co.; Commissioned by: Russell Brandt
- [Alterations to Office] - Permit Number: 71175, Address: 4011-4013 Hampton Blvd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1980-180 (Box 75, Folder 1218)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: R. L. Sykes Construction Co.; Commissioned by: Investors Management
- One Story, Two Bedroom Duplex - Permit Number: 71838, Address: 1268 W. 42nd St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-228 (Box 75, Folder 1219)
  Drawn by: Robert B. Lindemann, Certified Professional Engineer; Commissioned by: Bluestone Corp.
- Proposed Additions for Mr. and Mrs. Craig - Permit Number: 72052, Address: 451 Lee Point Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-303 (Box 75, Folder 1220)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: A. B. Wood and Son, Inc.; Commissioned by: Mr. and Mrs. Walter Craig
- [Signs for] Tidewater Distributing Co., Inc. - Permit Number: 73374-73375, Address: 1370 Ingleside Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-388 (Box 75, Folder 1221)
  Drawn by: Cardinal Sign Corp., 2629 Dean Dr., Virginia Beach, VA; Contractor: Cardinal Sign Corp.; Commissioned by: Hugh Barton
- Plans for Den Addition, 1506 Inwood Ave. - Permit Number: 71503, Address: 1506 Inwood Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1980-197 (Box 75, Folder 1222)
  Drawn by: Cary Jackson; Contractor: Carey F. Jackson; Commissioned by: Marcise Barongan
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 72495, Address: 3561 Trant Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 5; Tag Number: 1980-330 (Box 75, Folder 1223)
  Drawn by:; Contractor: J and B Contractor; Commissioned by: W. W. Harris
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 71807, Address: 839 Lesner Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1980-226 (Box 75, Folder 1224)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Mrs. Jay Taylor
- Proposed One Story, Three Bedroom - Permit Number: 71642, Address: 518 Louisa St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1980-211 (Box 75, Folder 1225)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: J. Pebworth
- Addition to the Residence of Jack and Leona Reilly - Permit Number: 71786, Address: 3708 Wedgefield Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 5; Tag Number: 1980-225 (Box 75, Folder 1226)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Superior Improvements, Inc.; Commissioned by: John Reilly
- One Story, Four Bedroom House - Permit Number: 72359, Address: 8345 Old Ocean View Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: 1980-321 (Box 75, Folder 1227)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Richard H. Dollar
- Residence of Mr. and MRs. Cole - Permit Number: 71862, Address: 2912 Earlscourt Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1980-230 (Box 75, Folder 1228)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Widener Construction Corp.
- [Residence] - Permit Number: 73419, Address: 9391 Granby St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: 1980-392 (Box 75, Folder 1229)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Hester Construction and Development Co.
- One Story, Two Bedroom Duplex - Permit Number: 70961, Address: 4203 Bowdens Ferry Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-169 (Box 75, Folder 1230)
- [Alterations to] Bayview Inn - Permit Number: 72129, Address: 8480 Chesapeake Blvd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 8; Tag Number: 1980-306 (Box 75, Folder 1231)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Thomas A. Clark
- Four Family Apartment - Permit Number: 71511, Address: 9634 Elnora St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1980-198 (Box 75, Folder 1232)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Hester Construction and Development Corp.
- Proposed Addition for Mr. and Mrs. Andrew L. Wilson - Permit Number: 71968, Address: 2308 Dominion Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1980-295 (Box 75, Folder 1233)
  Drawn by: W. A. Schmidt; Contractor: M. and J. Construction and Cabinet Co.; Commissioned by: Andrew L. Wilson
- New Elliot's - Permit Number: 71934, Address: 1421-1423 Colley Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 5; Tag Number: 1980-290 (Box 75, Folder 1234)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: LBW Contractors; Commissioned by: Elliott Benard
- Three Bedroom, Model B - Permit Number: 72491, Address: 2520 Minnesota Ave., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 5; Tag Number: 1980-328 (Box 75, Folder 1235)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Helfant Bros, Inc.
- [Alterations to D. J.'s Confectionary]] - Permit Number: 72367, Address: 3175-D Azalea Garden Rd., 1980, Media: Electrostatic prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-322 (Box 75, Folder 1236)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Monroe Case
- Two Bedroom Mini Ranch - Permit Number: 71631, Address: 5040 Lesselle Dr., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-206 (Box 75, Folder 1237)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: John W. Justice, Jr.
- [Duplex] - Permit Number: 73420, Address: 9395 Granby St., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-391 (Box 75, Folder 1238)
- [Single Family Residence] - Permit Number: 72118-72119, Address: 7846 Camellia Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 5; Tag Number: 1980-305 (Box 75, Folder 1239)
  Drawn by: A. C. Copeland, Jr.; Commissioned by: A. C. Copeland
- [Alterations to Residence] - Permit Number: 71704, Address: 1476 Willow Wood Dr., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: 1980-217 (Box 75, Folder 1240)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Surfside Builders, Inc.; Commissioned by: Michael Beoulieu
- [Warehouse Addition] - Permit Number: 55887, Address: 501 S. Main St., 1977, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1977-130 (Box 75, Folder 1241)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: C. S. I.; Commissioned by: P. H. Edwards, Inc.
- [Addition to D. A. V. Chapter House] Bernard L. Hines Chapter No. 21 and Auxiliary Disabled American Veterans - Permit Number: 72246, Address: 1010 W. Little Creek Rd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 12; Tag Number: 1980-313 (Box 75, Folder 1242)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: D. A. V. Chapter No. 21
- Duplex Residence[s] - Permit Number: 71403-71404, Address: 1814 and 1820 Lafayette Blvd., 1980, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1980-193 (Box 75, Folder 1243)
  Drawn by: W. A. Schmidt; Contractor: Junius Miller; Commissioned by: 4M Development Co.
- [Storage Tank and Earthen Dikes] - Permit Number: 56667, Address: N. E. Corner Reville and Lansing Sts., 1977, Media: Diazo prints, Electrostatic prints; Sheets: 14; Tag Number: 1977-202 (Box 75, Folder 1244)
  Drawn by: Richmond Engineering Co., Inc., Richmond, VA; Commissioned by: Chemphalt of Carolina, Inc.
- [Residence] The "York" - Permit Number: 61912-61913, 63316-63319, 63875-63876, 64669-64697, 67478-67479, 67938-67940, Address: 1400, 1418, 1430, 1448 Arbor Ave.; 1307, 1319, 1331, 1349, 1407, 1419, 1443 Branch Rd.; 6854, 6861 Orangewood Ave.; 6848 W. Tanners Creek Rd.; 6825, 6833 Cedarwood Ct., 1979, Media: Diazo prints; Sheets: 8; Tag Number: None (Box 75, Folder 1245)
  Drawn by: Dan E. Griffin, A.I.A.; Commissioned by: Gideon Enterprises, Inc.; Notes: Permit # 67478-67479, 10/12/1979, (1979-457); Permit # 64669-64697, 3/15/1979, (1979-099); Permit # 63875-63876, 12/18/1979, (1979-503); Permit # 67938-67940, 9/12/1979, (1979-408); Permit # 61912-61913, 7/21/1979, (1979-262); Permit # 63316-63319, 10/31/1979, (1979-430)
- Tabernacle Church - Permit Number: 64825, Address: 7120 Granby St., 1951, Media: Blueprints, Diazo prints; Sheets: 11; Tag Number: None (Box 75, Folder 1246)
  Drawn by: G. L. Duern, A.C.I.D.; Commissioned by: Tabernacle Church.